Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And today, Marco, we're talking about some very special places, right?
今天，Marco，我们要聊一些非常特别的地方，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about the famous list of the seven wonders of the world.
今天我们要讨论著名的世界七大奇迹名单。
So you've probably heard about this before.
你可能以前听说过这个。
We're not going to tell you what this means quite yet.
我们暂时不会告诉你这具体是什么意思。
Take a listen to today's dialogue.
先听听今天的对话吧。
And when we come back, we'll talk a little bit more about what these wonders are and
等我们回来，再详细聊聊这些奇迹是什么，
where they are.
以及它们在哪里。
Have you seen this news article?
你看到这篇新闻文章了吗？
Apparently an organization has made a list to name the new seven wonders of the world
显然有个组织列了一份名单，评选世界新七大奇迹，
and people could vote for them online.
人们可以在网上投票。
Wow, that's really interesting.
哇，这真有意思。
So who would?
那都有哪些呢？
Well, the Great Wall of China, the Taj Mahal in India.
嗯，有中国的长城、印度的泰姬陵。
I've been there.
我去过那里。
It really is an amazing work of architecture and art.
那真是一件令人惊叹的建筑和艺术杰作。
The entire complex is made of white marble and in the interior of the tomb, the walls
整个建筑群由白色大理石建成，陵墓内部墙壁
are covered with gems and emeralds.
镶嵌着宝石和翡翠。
Cool.
酷。
Also amongst the winners is Petra in Jordan, Machu Picchu in Peru, and the pyramid in Chichen
入选的还有约旦的佩特拉、秘鲁的马丘比丘，以及墨西哥奇琴伊察
Itza in Mexico.
的金字塔。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
It also says that the Christ Redeemer statue in Brazil and the Colosseum in Rome are wonders.
文章还说巴西的基督救世主雕像和罗马的斗兽场也是奇迹。
I would love to go to Italy and see the Colosseum, stand in the middle like a gladiator.
我真想去意大利看看斗兽场，像角斗士一样站在中间。
Well, let's see if we can find some cheap airfare and we can go towards the end of the
嗯，我们看看能不能找到便宜的机票，然后年底
year.
去一趟。
Good idea.
好主意。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So let's talk about these very interesting places all over the world.
那么我们来聊聊这些遍布世界各地的有趣地方吧。
Now on Language Takeaway.
现在是“语言要点”环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So the set phrase for this, Marco, is the seven wonders of the world.
Marco，这个固定短语是“世界七大奇迹”。
Now the key here is the word wonder.
这里的关键词是“奇迹”。
What is a wonder?
什么是奇迹？
Right.
对。
A wonder is something very amazing, incredible.
奇迹是非常惊人、不可思议的东西。
It's something that's beyond your imagination almost.
它几乎超乎你的想象。
That's right.
没错。
You can't even imagine how man or how someone created it.
你甚至无法想象人类是如何建造出它的。
And so wonderful is a similar word that's an adjective, something that's just great,
而“wonderful”是一个类似的形容词，意思是极好的、
fantastic is wonderful.
美妙的。
A wonder is something very, very special.
奇迹是非常非常特别的东西。
And here we have seven of them.
而这里我们有七个。
That's right.
没错。
And it's a list basically that you can see even online about these wonders all over the
这基本上是一个名单，你甚至可以在网上看到这些遍布世界的奇迹，
world and they're so special because they are amazing works of art and architecture.
它们之所以特别，是因为它们是令人惊叹的艺术和建筑杰作。
And starting off with one of the most famous ones is in China.
我们先从最著名的一个说起，它在中国。
It's the Great Wall of China.
那就是中国的长城。
I think what's special about this I've heard is that when astronauts are in space, it's
我听说它的特别之处在于，宇航员在太空中，
so long and so distinct they can actually see the Great Wall.
因为它又长又显眼，实际上能看到长城。
Yeah, that's what I've heard as well.
嗯，我也听说过。
It's a very long wall, thousands of kilometers long.
它是一道非常长的城墙，绵延数千公里。
That's right.
没错。
And it goes east to west all across the northern border of China.
它从东到西横跨中国北部边境。
That's right.
没错。
So it's a very big wall.
所以它是一道非常大的城墙。
And what's interesting about it is that it was built such a long time ago and that the
有趣的是，它是在很久以前建造的，而且
techniques used to make it were very special.
建造技术非常特别。
That's right.
没错。
And sometimes you might hear us talk about the Great Wall instead of the Great Wall of
有时候你可能会听到我们只说“长城”，而不是“中国的长城”。
China.
And so that's just a hint.
这只是个提示。
It's easy to say Great Wall.
说“长城”很简单。
You can say them both ways though.
不过两种说法都可以。
Exactly.
没错。
Now moving west towards India, we have another very amazing work of architecture.
现在往西到印度，我们有另一项非常惊人的建筑杰作。
It's called the Taj Mahal.
它叫泰姬陵。
Now the Taj Mahal is in North India in a city called Agra.
泰姬陵位于印度北部一个叫阿格拉的城市。
And it's very special because it's massive, it's very big, and it's all white marble.
它非常特别，因为它规模宏大，非常巨大，而且全部由白色大理石建成。
That's right.
没错。
And it's interesting because this place, the Taj Mahal, is not really a temple.
有趣的是，泰姬陵这个地方其实不是寺庙。
It was actually a tomb.
它实际上是一座陵墓。
All right.
好的。
Now that's an interesting word to look at.
现在来看一个有趣的词。
A tomb is a place where we bury someone, you know, after someone dies.
“陵墓”是埋葬死者的地方，你知道，人去世之后。
Maybe if you have a lot of money, you're very rich, you want to put that body in a very
也许如果你很有钱，非常富有，你想把遗体放在一个非常
special sacred place.
特别神圣的地方。
And that's called a tomb.
那叫做陵墓。
That's right.
没错。
So this is actually what the Taj Mahal is.
所以这就是泰姬陵的实际样子。
Now we saw in the dialogue that the entire complex of the Taj Mahal is made of white
我们在对话中看到，泰姬陵的整个建筑群是由白色
marble.
大理石建成的。
So when we talk about the entire complex, what do we mean?
那么当我们说整个建筑群时，指的是什么？
Well complex here is a noun.
这里的“complex”是一个名词。
You might have heard it in other situations where it's an adjective, it means something
你可能在其他情况下听过它作为形容词，意思
different.
不同。
But here a complex means many buildings together, right?
但在这里，“complex”指的是许多建筑在一起，对吧？
So you can say the Taj Mahal is one building.
所以你可以说泰姬陵是一座建筑。
But the Taj Mahal complex maybe has four or five buildings together.
但泰姬陵建筑群可能包含四五座建筑。
So a side temple and a gatehouse.
比如一座侧殿和一座门楼。
And so we say a complex is a grouping of buildings.
所以我们说“complex”是一组建筑的集合。
That's right.
没错。
Very good.
很好。
So now let's move on.
那么现在我们继续。
Let's take a look at Language Takeaway Part 2 and let's continue talking about these wonders
让我们看看“语言要点”第二部分，继续讨论这些世界
of the world.
奇观。
Now the top of our list in Language Takeaway Part 2 is actually a place I would love to
在“语言要点”第二部分中，排在第一位的其实是一个我很想
go to.
去的地方。
I've never been there.
我从来没去过那里。
It's in Jordan, which is a country in the Middle East and it's called Petra.
它在约旦，一个中东国家，叫做佩特拉。
Petra.
佩特拉。
That's right.
没错。
So it's actually a city but it's also known as the lost city of Petra, right?
它实际上是一座城市，但也被称为失落的佩特拉城，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And what's unique about this city is that the city is built.
这座城市的独特之处在于它是建成的。
It's carved out of stone in this cliff.
它是从悬崖上的石头中雕刻出来的。
So it's not just pieces of stone put together.
所以不是用石块拼凑起来的。
It's actually inside the rocks.
它实际上是在岩石内部。
Exactly.
正是。
So it's very famous.
所以它非常有名。
You've probably seen it in movies like Indiana Jones.
你可能在《夺宝奇兵》这样的电影里见过它。
There's a big part of the scenes that go on inside Petra.
电影中有很大一部分场景是在佩特拉内部进行的。
Very special place and again very unique.
一个非常特别的地方，而且非常独特。
Now the next site is actually very far away in South America and again it's ancient and
下一个景点其实很远，在南美洲，同样古老且
very intricate.
非常精致。
It's called Machu Picchu.
它叫做马丘比丘。
That's right.
没错。
So this is in one of those very old cities that are actually in ruins now and the interesting
所以这是那些古老城市之一，现在已成废墟，有趣的是
thing about it is that it's very high up in like a little mountain.
它位于一座小山上，非常高。
And those mountains there, those are the Andes, right?
那些山是安第斯山脉，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So Machu Picchu, also a very famous place.
所以马丘比丘，也是一个非常有名的地方。
Many visitors from all over the world go there as well.
来自世界各地的许多游客也去那里。
And another main attraction around the world are the pyramids.
世界上的另一个主要景点是金字塔。
So we have some pyramids in Egypt.
我们在埃及有一些金字塔。
I think those are the most well-known ones.
我认为那些是最著名的。
That's right.
没错。
The pyramids in Egypt like the Pyramid of Giza are very big structures.
埃及的金字塔，比如吉萨金字塔，是非常巨大的建筑。
I mean they're huge and they were built thousands of years ago but they're still here because
我的意思是它们非常庞大，建于几千年前，但至今仍然存在，因为
they were built so well.
它们建造得非常好。
But there are also very famous pyramids like the one we heard about today in the dialogue
但也有非常著名的金字塔，比如我们今天在对话中听到的
in Mexico.
墨西哥的那个。
That's right.
没错。
It's a little bit different though because the pyramids as we, most of us know them,
不过它有点不同，因为我们大多数人知道的金字塔，
they're very smooth on the sides you would say.
可以说侧面非常光滑。
Yeah, you can't climb on them really, right?
是的，你基本上不能爬上去，对吧？
Right.
对。
Well this one in Mexico actually has kind of like steps.
而墨西哥的这个实际上有点像台阶。
So it's a different type of pyramid but the shape is very similar.
所以它是一种不同类型的金字塔，但形状非常相似。
Alright.
好的。
So the pyramids here are in a place called Chichen Itza.
这里的金字塔位于一个叫奇琴伊察的地方。
You might have heard of that.
你可能听说过那里。
And we have another place though which is also in South America in the city of Rio de
我们还有另一个地方，也在南美洲，在里约热内卢
Janeiro.
市。
Now this one is actually a statue, right?
这个实际上是一座雕像，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
It's called the Christ Redeemer.
它叫做基督救世主像。
It's a very big statue, very famous.
是一座非常大的雕像，非常有名。
You've seen it maybe in pictures.
你可能在照片里见过它。
It's a statue of Jesus with his arms open.
是一座耶稣张开双臂的雕像。
Now the word Redeemer, okay, a Redeemer is a person, someone who does something, who
“救世主”这个词，嗯，救世主是一个人，一个做某事的人，一个
redeems.
救赎的人。
What does it mean to be a Redeemer?
成为救世主意味着什么？
Well, a Redeemer is a person that saves souls for example.
嗯，救世主是拯救灵魂的人，比如。
So if you redeem yourself, you're redeeming yourself of your sins maybe.
所以如果你自我救赎，你就是在救赎自己的罪过。
Well yeah, you're taking value back, right?
嗯，是的，你在找回价值，对吧？
And so in the case of Jesus, he is taking away the sins of the world and he's redeeming,
所以在耶稣的情况下，他带走世人的罪过，进行救赎。
you know, that's why his arms are out.
你知道，这就是为什么他的手臂是张开的。
He's redeeming all people.
他在救赎所有人。
And that's the idea I think behind the Christ Redeemer statue.
我认为这就是基督救世主雕像背后的理念。
So the verb redeem, like you can use it in everyday life if you take a coupon and you
所以动词 redeem，就像你在日常生活中可以用它，如果你拿一张优惠券然后
redeem it.
兑换它。
That means you, yeah, you collect the value.
那意味着你，是的，你获得了价值。
You collect the value, right?
你获得了价值，对吧？
So you can use it, actually this word in everyday life.
所以实际上你可以在日常生活中使用这个词。
You can.
可以的。
And moving on now towards Europe, we have the famous Colosseum.
现在继续往欧洲看，我们有著名的罗马斗兽场。
Ooh, now I love this one.
哦，这个我喜欢。
I've actually been there and I know you have too recently.
我实际上去过那里，我知道你最近也去过。
But this is a circular, like a round stadium.
这是一个圆形的，像一个圆形体育场。
So it's a place where you play sports.
所以这是一个进行体育活动的地方。
Well, you did.
嗯，以前是的。
It was from, you know, thousands of years ago, the Roman Empire.
它来自几千年前，罗马帝国时期。
And it's in very good shape I would say.
而且我觉得它保存得非常好。
You can still see it.
你现在还能看到它。
Yeah.
是的。
So it's actually called the Colosseum, although a Colosseum as we know it now can also be
所以它实际上叫罗马斗兽场，虽然我们现在知道的斗兽场也可以指
the same thing, right?
同样的东西，对吧？
A structure where sports or activities are played.
一个进行体育或活动的建筑结构。
Basically, yeah, a Colosseum is an old stadium.
基本上，是的，斗兽场就是一个古老的体育场。
But the Colosseum, like you said, is definitely the Colosseum in Rome.
但就像你说的，罗马斗兽场特指罗马的那个。
That's right.
没错。
And we've probably seen movies of ancient Rome where sports or activities were taking
我们可能看过一些关于古罗马的电影，里面进行着体育或活动，
place, specifically gladiator fights.
特别是角斗士战斗。
So that's our word there, gladiator.
所以这就是我们的词，角斗士。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
A gladiator is actually a person.
角斗士实际上是一个人。
And a gladiator was a man who thousands of years ago during the Roman Empire would fight
角斗士是几千年前罗马帝国时期的人，他会与
maybe other men or animals and he had to fight to stay alive.
其他人或动物战斗，他必须战斗才能活下来。
So that was his profession basically, to be a gladiator.
所以这基本上就是他的职业，当一名角斗士。
So now as you are a boxer, back then you were a gladiator.
所以现在你是拳击手，以前你就是角斗士。
Yeah.
是的。
And there are actually some very famous movies about gladiators, like the movie Gladiator
实际上有一些非常著名的关于角斗士的电影，比如罗素·克劳主演的
with Russell Crowe.
电影《角斗士》。
So it's a pretty common word these days.
所以现在这个词挺常见的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So let's take a break.
那我们休息一下。
We'll be back in a bit.
我们一会儿回来。
Have you seen this news article?
你看到这篇新闻文章了吗？
Apparently, an organization has made a list to name the new seven wonders of the world
显然，有一个组织列了一个名单来命名世界新七大奇迹，
and people could vote for them online.
人们可以在网上投票。
Wow, that's really interesting.
哇，那真有趣。
So who would?
那谁会入选呢？
Well, the Great Wall of China, the Taj Mahal in India.
嗯，中国的长城，印度的泰姬陵。
I've been there.
我去过那里。
It really is an amazing work of architecture and art.
它真的是一个令人惊叹的建筑和艺术杰作。
The entire world is in it.
整个世界都融入了其中。
And it's a great place to be.
那是一个很棒的地方。
I've been there.
我去过那里。
it was voted online.
它是通过网上投票选出的。
People all over the world out of different candidates or different places that were considered
全世界的人们从不同的候选地或被认为
to be the new seven wonders of the world.
是世界新七大奇迹的地方中投票。
Among those, like some of them that didn't win for example was Angkor Wat in Cambodia.
其中，一些没有入选的，比如柬埔寨的吴哥窟。
Yeah, I never understood that.
是啊，我一直不理解。
I think Angkor Wat is such an amazing place and so big and it was the heart of this old civilization.
我觉得吴哥窟是一个如此神奇的地方，那么大，而且是这个古老文明的中心。
And instead we have other things like a statue.
结果我们却选了其他东西，比如一个雕像。
Yeah, I don't agree with it as well.
是啊，我也不同意。
But actually the Statue of Liberty of the United States was also considered as a candidate for a wonder of the world.
但实际上美国的自由女神像也曾被考虑作为世界奇迹的候选。
Well, that's right. America doesn't have any wonders.
嗯，没错。美国没有什么奇迹。
You have natural wonders I think. The Grand Canyon is considered I think one of those natural wonders.
你们有自然奇观，我觉得。大峡谷被认为是自然奇观之一。
Yes, I think Niagara Falls also maybe.
是的，我觉得尼亚加拉大瀑布可能也算。
But that's an interesting point though, Marco.
但马可，那是个有趣的观点。
We've got the great wonders of the world and we've got the natural wonders.
我们有世界伟大奇观，还有自然奇观。
What's the difference?
有什么区别呢？
Well, a natural wonder of the world means that it's there naturally.
嗯，世界自然奇观指的是天然形成的。
It's not man-made.
不是人造的。
All of these things that we see here, somebody had to make them.
我们看到的这些东西，都是有人建造的。
Whereas for example the Grand Canyon or Niagara Falls, they are there naturally.
而比如大峡谷或尼亚加拉瀑布，它们是天然存在的。
It's by nature.
是自然形成的。
All right. So man-made versus natural or made by nature.
好的。所以是人造与天然的区别。
Right. So it's very interesting because you have like we said natural seven wonders of the world.
对。这很有趣，因为就像我们说的，有世界七大自然奇观。
You have these, the new ones.
还有这些新的奇观。
You have the ancient world wonders which like none of them exist anymore.
还有古代世界奇观，它们现在几乎都不存在了。
I think only the pyramids.
我想只有金字塔还在。
That's right. The hanging gardens of Babylon and the colossus at Rhodes.
没错。巴比伦空中花园和罗得岛巨像。
Yeah.
嗯。
Yeah, those ones are very cool but not like you said, not around anymore.
是啊，那些很酷，但就像你说的，已经不复存在了。
But maybe some of you actually, maybe your countries were considered to host one of these wonders or maybe you voted for some of them.
不过也许你们中有些人，你们的国家被认为拥有这些奇观之一，或者你们为其中一些投过票。
Yeah, let us know.
是啊，告诉我们吧。
What is a wonder where you come from?
你家乡有什么奇观？
It doesn't have to be on this list.
不一定非得在这个名单上。
It can be something you think is wonderful.
可以是任何你觉得奇妙的东西。
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right. We'll see you guys there.
好的。我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。
English translation by CastingWords
英文翻译由CastingWords提供。